Finding Aid for Jeanne Tashian papers, 1970-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Jeanne Tashian papers 1970-1973
Tashian, Jeanne.
1 linear foot
85447 Aa 2
Teacher, writer, member of feminist organizations. Materials relating to her involvement with the University of Michigan Commission for Women, Ann Arbor Focus on Equal Opportunity for Women, PROBE into the Status of Women at The University of Michigan, and the Ad Hoc Committee Concerned That President Fleming Does Not Meet With Women.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Jeanne Tashian (donor no. 6379 ).
No furtehr additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Jeanne Tashian was co-editor of the newsletter of the University of Michigan Commission for Women. She began as a secretary, then as editorial assistant and eventually co-editor of the Women's Information Network Bulletin. Tashian was also an active member of Ann Arbor Focus on Equal Opportunity for Women and founding member of PROBE into the Status of Women at the University of Michigan. She served as general coordinator of the Ad Hoc Committee Concerned That President Fleming Does Not Meet With Women. Other activities included being student representative on the University's Doctor of Arts Admissions Committee. She was also instrumental in developing the job of women's advocate with the University Office of Student Organizations and in the attempt to organize clerical workers at the University of Michigan into a union.
The papers of Jeanne Tashian, 1970-1976, primarily relate to the feminist movement in Ann Arbor and at the University of Michigan between 1970 and 1973. Most of the files relate to her various organizational interests and activities.
Subjects:
Ad Hoc Committee Concerned That President Fleming Does Not Meet With Women (University of Michigan); Affirmative action programs--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor Focus on Equal Opportunity for Women.; Discrimination in employment--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; PROBE into the Status of Women at The University of Michigan.; University of Michigan. Commission for Women.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Women's rights--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; College teachers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women college teachers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Personal
  - Biographical data (Box 1)
  - Writings, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 1)
  - Class materials (Box 1)
- Organizational files
  - Ann Arbor Focus on Equal Opportunity For Women, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Job Discrimination, legal information (Box 1)
  - PROBE into the Status of Women at The University of Michigan, 1970-1971, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Concerned That President Fleming Does Not Meet With Women, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Program for the Employment of Women, ca, 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Center For Continuing Education of Women, 1970 (Box 1)
  - U-M Commission For Women
    - General, undated and 1971-1973, 7 folders (Box 1)
    - Cluster Groups (Box 1)
    - Women's Information Network Bulletin, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - The Feminine Mistake: Women at The University of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Labor Organization at the University of Michigan, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Office of Student Organizations, ca. 1970 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous re. the University of Michigan (Box 1)
  - W.E.A.L. (Women's Equity Action League), ca. 1970 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)